Ruth Clifford Engs papers, 1947-2010 C404
Indiana University Archives
- Research, writing and professional activities files, 1963-2015; undated (Box 1)
  - Book Files, 1991-2001 (Box 5)
    - Unseen Upton Sinclair, 2007-2010 (Box 7)
      - Publisher (McFarland & Co.), 2008-2010 (Box 7)
      - John Ahouse and Anthony Arthur, 2008-2010 (Box 7)
      - Book Reviews and Media Reports, 2009 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence with Fans and Students, 2009-2010 (Box 7)
      - Emails and Drafts – CD, 2007-2010 (Box 7)
      - Final Draft to McFarland & Co., 2008 (Box 7)
  - General Book and Publication Files, 1978-2001 (Box 7)
    - Responsible Drug and Alcohol Use – Correspondence, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Women: Alcohol and Other Drugs – Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Controversies in the Addictions Field – Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 7)
    - Alcohol Use in Cultural and Historical Perspectives – Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
    - Alcohol and other Drugs: Self-Responsibility – Correspondence, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Personal Health Study Guide – Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - Alcohol use and abuse among youth – Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
    - Past Influences, Current Issues – Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 7)
  - Unpublished Handouts, 1979-1992 (Box 7)
    - Alcohol Abuse or Alcoholism?, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Alcoholism: Prevention, Intervention and Treatment in Special Populations, undated (Box 7)
    - The Code Checklist for Identifying Codependency, undated (Box 7)
    - Co‑dependence: What Is it and How Do I Know I Have It, undated (Box 7)
    - Definition of Alcoholism and Type of Alcoholics, undated (Box 7)
    - Drinking Related Problems of College Students, undated (Box 7)
    - The Educated Person, undated (Box 7)
    - Identifying Co-dependency Among University Students, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Instigating a Substance Intervention Workshop, undated (Box 7)
    - Interview Skills for Health Educators, undated (Box 7)
    - National Study Data Tables, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Overlapping Effects of Drugs and Symptoms of Drug Actions, undated (Box 7)
    - Personal Risk Prediction Checklist, undated (Box 7)
    - Possible Family Dynamics Leading to Co-dependency, undated (Box 7)
    - Quick Alcoholism Diagnostic Checklist, undated (Box 7)
    - Quick Diagnostic Checklist for Alcohol/Drug Chronic Abuse, undated (Box 7)
    - Relationship Between Q-F Level and Sex, Race and College Class, undated (Box 7)
    - Risk of Getting Alcoholism and its Natural Course, undated (Box 7)
    - The Risk of Having or Getting Alcoholism, undated (Box 7)
    - Role of the Immediate Supervisor, undated (Box 7)
    - Small Group Confrontation Situations, undated (Box 7)
    - Small Group Confrontation Situations for Nurses, undated (Box 7)
    - Small Group Discussion for College Students, undated (Box 7)
    - Statements Common Among Alcoholics, undated (Box 7)
    - Student Intervention Checklist for Resident Assistants, undated (Box 7)
    - Survey Information Required for Baseline Data in Campus Alcohol Education Program, undated (Box 7)
    - Various Definitions of Co-dependency, undated (Box 7)
  - Unpublished or Not Accepted Essays or Op-Eds, 1989-2002 (Box 7)
    - One around again?, (estimate: 1989-1991) (Box 7)
    - Are we doomed to repeat history…again?, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Our soldiers: Prisoners of the Gulf?, 1991 (Box 7)
    - What happened to scholarship?: The rise of the new McCarthyism, Early 1990s (Box 7)
    - The new Dark Ages: Controlling what you eat and drink, 1994 (Box 7)
    - The challenges of health 'overkill', 1994 (Box 7)
    - The carrot-juice patrol: are we becoming health fascists?, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Raising taxes on alcoholic beverages is not the answer for curbing alcohol abuse among youth, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Unpublished or Not Accepted Research Articles/Book Chapters/Books, 1974-1996; undated (Box 7)
    - Articles, 1974-1996 (Box 7)
      - Effects of exposure to a school health simulation/game, (roughly 1974-1975) (Box 7)
      - What does the health concern questionnaire really tell us?, 1979 (Box 7)
      - The effect of endurance and participatory activity university courses on state and trait anxiety scores, 1979 (Box 7)
      - Alcoholism: Prevention, Intervention and Treatment in Special Population Groups, rejected manuscript, 1981; (2 folders) (Box 7)
      - Predicting drinking related problems of college students, 1984 (Box 7)
      - The presence or absence of Roman influence on drinking patterns: A model to explain difference in Western society, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
        General
        f
      - Wine loving Romans and beer bashing barbarians: The origins of drinking norms in Western society, 1991 (Box 7)
        RESTRICTED
      - Western drinking norms: Are the rooted in Roman and barbarian antiquity?, 1992 (Box 7)
      - Is there an association of heavy drinking with illness among college students if smoking status is controlled?, 1993 (Box 7)
      - The relationship of the temperance and other clean living movements: 1820-1870, 1995-96 (Box 7)
    - Book, 1981; undated (Box 7)
      - Alcoholism: Prevention, Intervention, and Treatment in Special Population Groups (Box 7)
        - Completed Draft (Box 7)
          - Chapters 1-4, 1981 (Box 7)
          - Chapters 5-14, 1981 (Box 7)
        - Rough Draft and Related Materials (Box 7)
          - Chapter 1, undated (Box 7)
          - Chapter 2, undated; (2 folders) (Box 7)
          - Chapter 4, undated (Box 7)
          - Chapter 5, undated (Box 8)
          - Chapter 6, undated (Box 8)
          - Chapter 7, undated (Box 8)
          - Chapter 8, undated (Box 8)
          - Chapter 14, undated (Box 8)
          - Alternate Chapter 7, undated (Box 8)
          - Alternate Chapter 8, undated (Box 8)
          - Alternate Chapter 9, undated (Box 8)
        - Unused Materials, undated; (3 folders) (Box 8)
        - Related Notes and Materials, undated; (4 folders) (Box 8)
  - Unaccepted Book Proposals, 1974-1993 (Box 8)
    - Responsible Drinking and Sex, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Treating Addictive Behaviors, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Elementary Health Education, 1988 (Box 8)
    - The Presence or Absence of Roman Influence on Drinking Patterns: A Model to Explain Differences in Western Society, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Personal Health Book, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Applied Epidemiology, 1993 (Box 8)
    - The Mystery of a Healthy Life: A Family Health Guide, undated (Box 8)
  - Not Started or Incomplete Research, 1978-2006 (Box 8)
    - Marijuana, Immediate Memory, and Driving Performance, a Pilot Study – William J. Bailey, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Study with Dave Anderson, 1986-1988 (Box 8)
    - Warning Labels on Alcoholic Beverages: A Counterproductive Method to Prevent Alcohol Abuse, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Dave Tanner – Bicycle Trip Interview, 1989 (Box 8)
    - British Co-dependency Study, 1989 (Box 8)
    - International Study of Student Drinking Patterns (Box 8)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 8)
      - Data Correlation, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
    - Africa – Transmission of Drinking Culture Study (Box 8)
      - 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box 8)
      - Data, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Thailand – Student Worry Study, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Hormone Replacement Therapy Student, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Compulsive Shopping Study, 2005-2006 (Box 8)
  - Conference Programs and Proceedings, 1978-2003 (Box 8)
    - Conference Programs (Box 8)
      - 1978-1988 (Box 8)
      - 1975-2003 (Box 9)
      - 1988 (Box 9)
    - Conference Abstracts, 1980-1997 (Box 9)
    - Iceland Conference (Did Not Attend), 1997 (Box 9)
    - Permission for Pleasure Conference (Did Not Attend), 1998 (Box 9)
  - Original Artwork, Photographs, and Illustrations (Box 9)
    - Original Artwork, Photographs, and Illustrations, undated; (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Original Artwork, Photographs, and Illustrations, undated; (OVERSIZED BOX) (Box 9)
    - European Map of Viticulture for Origins of Drinking Culture Works, undated (Box 9)
    - Adam and Eve Artwork for Forbidden Fruit Article, undated (Box 9)
  - Service Committees and Projects, 1971-1997; undated (Box 9)
    - Medical Aid Station, 1971 (Box 9)
    - Development of IU Booze and Yous Program, 1974-1982 (Box 9)
    - Untangling a line – or -- The joint cooperation of a local mental health association with students in establishing a teenage telephone crisis intervention center, undated (Box 9)
    - Neighborhood Counseling Program – News Clippings, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Alcohol & Drug Problems Association of North America, 1983 (Box 9)
    - American Council on Alcoholism, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Moderation Management Network Inc., 1994 (Box 9)
    - National Association for Sport and Physical Education, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
    - Research Ranks Promotion Review Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Grant Proposals and Award Submissions, 1975-2002 (Box 9)
    - Alcohol Awareness – Spencer Grant, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Training Bartenders, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence with NIAAA about Alcohol Education Grant Proposals, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Post-doctorate Teaching Fellowship Program Proposal, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Approaches to accountability in prevention: The possible success of targeting high risk individuals to prevent drug and alcohol abuse, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Validation of self-reporting of alcohol use by biological and observational monitoring, 1988 (Box 9)
    - The drinking, drug use, and lifestyle patterns of Ontario university students: Phase I - Addiction Research Foundation proposal, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Research Award Submission, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Drinking patterns at the international level: A test of hypotheses, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Self-reported alcohol consumption in relationship to immune function, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - Self-reported alcohol consumption in relationship to immune function Correspondence with and drafts for Marlene Aldo-Benson, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - Department of Applied Health Sciences research grand-in-aid application, 1993-1999 (Box 9)
    - Knee exercise study, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Workshop Presentation & Outline Files, 1988-1999; undated (Box 9)
    - Assorted Tables/Charts, 1988-1999 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Keys for Data Entry, undated (Box 9)
    - Weight and Hypnosis, undated (Box 9)
    - Notes for Clean Living Presentations, undated (Box 9)
    - Drug and Alcohol Intervention, undated (Box 9)
    - How effective is presenting information in changing a health behavior?: Implications from the health belief model, undated (Box 9)
    - Warning Labels on Alcoholic Beverages, undated (Box 9)
    - Alcohol and Drug-related Training Materials, Late 1980s-1990s (Box 9)
    - Family Background Co-dependency Lectures, undated (Box 10)
    - Roman/Barbarian & Clean Living Materials, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Reviews Written by Ruth Engs, 1991-2014; undated (Box 10)
    - Adolescent Drinking and Family Life, 1991 (Box 10)
    - The Alchemy of Culture: Intoxicants in Society, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Amphetamine Misuse: International Perspectives on Current Trends, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Assorted Reviews, 1994-1999; undated (Box 10)
    - The progressive era's health reform movement: a historical dictionary, 2003 (Box 10)
    - Brave New World: Eugenics between Science and Ideology, 2006; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Myth of Race Relations by R. Sussman, 2014 (Box 10)
- Correspondence Files, 1970s-2012; undated (Box 10)
  - Specific Correspondence, 1970s-2012; undated (Box 10)
    - Addiction Research Foundation, 1996 (Box 10)
    - Address Book, undated (Box 10)
    - Bowen, Otis R., 1981 (Box 10)
    - Daniels, Dennis, 1998-1999; (2 folders) (Box 10)
      RESTRICTED TO 2023
    - Debate/Clarification of Ideas, 1988-2001 (Box 10)
    - Digital files, 2012 (Box 10)
    - Health Fair Controversy, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Email Samples from Drinking File, 2000-2003 (Box 10)
    - General Correspondence, 1970s-2012 (Box 10)
      - 1970s (Box 10)
      - 1980s (Box 10)
      - 1990s (Box 10)
      - 2000s, (6 folders) (Box 10)
      - Select Correspondence Through, 2009; genreform: Compact Disc (Box 10)
    - Hanson, David, 1985-2001 (Box 10)
    - Hanson, David, 1989-2000 (Box 10)
    - Indiana University-related Correspondence, 1973-2002 (Box 10)
    - Individuals asking for help with addictive behaviors, 2012 (Box 10)
      RESTRICTED TO 2038
    - Leonard, Mike, 2011 (Box 10)
      MAY BE READ WITH PERMISSION OF MIKE LEONARD
    - Letters (email) (Box 10)
      - General, 1997-2003 (Box 10)
      - Media, 1997-2012; (7 folders) (Box 10)
    - Magic, undated (Box 10)
    - McCloskey, Frank, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Nasty or Hostile Letters Regarding Research, Presentations, and Opinions, 1975-2002 (Box 10)
    - Nice or Supportive Letters Regarding Research, Presentations, and Opinions, 1985-1999 (Box 10)
    - Personal, 1983-1991 (Box 10)
      RESTRICTED TO 2030
    - Personal, 1992-2000 (Box 10)
    - Personal, 1999-2003 (Box 10)
    - Quest File – Miscellaneous Questions, 1999-2003 (Box 10)
    - Retirement Announcements, 2003 (Box 10)
    - Review of Department Chair Candidates - Pre-tenure, undated (Box 10)
    - Rome Hypothesis, 1990-1997 (Box 10)
    - Ruth Clifford Engs Lecture Series, 2010-2012 (Box 10)
    - Students, 2012; (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Student Alcohol Questionnaire, 1996-2003 (Box 10a)
    - Shopping Addiction, 2002-2003 (Box 10a)
    - Sphincter of Oddi Questions, 2000-2003 (Box 10a)
    - University of Vermont, 1999-2003 (Box 10a)
    - Wales/Scotland Visit, 1986 (Box 10a)
    - Wall Street Journal Article – Clarifications, 1991 (Box 10a)
- Teaching Files, 1981-2001 (Box 10a)
  - Indiana University Teaching Files, 1981-2001 (Box 10a)
    - General, 1981-2001 (Box 10a)
      - Teacher Evaluations, 1995-2001 (Box 10a)
      - Workshop on Alcoholism, Drug Use, and Alcohol/Drug Education, 1981-1987 (Box 10a)
      - Health Education in Clinical Settings, 1984 (Box 10a)
      - Alcohol and Drug Workshop Assignments, 1988 (Box 10a)
      - Health and Communication Over the Lifespan: Individual and Family (Box 10a)
        - Study Guide, 1994 (Box 10a)
        - Syllabus and Exams, 1994 (Box 10a)
      - Research Methods – Study Guide and Lecture Notes, 2000 (Box 10a)
    - Personal Health (H363) Teaching Files, 1988-1999; undated (Box 11)
      - Syllabus, 1988-1999 (Box 11)
        - 1988 (Box 11)
        - 1991 (Box 11)
        - Spring 1995 (Box 11)
        - Fall 1995 (Box 11)
        - Spring 1996 (Box 11)
        - Fall 1996 (Box 11)
        - Spring 1997 (Box 11)
        - Fall 1997 (Box 11)
        - Spring 1998 (Box 11)
        - Spring 1999 (Box 11)
      - Exams, 1990's; (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Materials/Lecture Notes for Exam I, undated (Box 11)
      - Materials/Lecture Notes for Exam II, undated (Box 11)
      - Materials/Lecture Notes for Exam III, undated (Box 11)
      - Assorted Teaching/Visual Materials, undated (Box 11)
      - Assorted Teaching/Visual Materials, undated (Box 11)
        (OVERSIZED BOX)
      - Health Hints Course Book, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Human Diseases and Epidemiology, 1988-1993; undated (Box 11)
      - General Information and Materials, 1988-1993; (5 folders) (Box 11)
      - Assignments, Labs, and Exercises, 1991 (Box 11)
      - Exam Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
      - Study Guide, 1993 (Box 11)
      - Teaching and Visual Materials, undated (Box 11)
        - General, undated (Box 11)
        - Basic/Introduction, undated (Box 11)
      - Terminology, undated (Box 11)
      - Rates and Statistics, undated (Box 11)
      - Data Source, undated (Box 11)
      - Morbidity/Mortality, undated (Box 11)
      - Food/Water & Infectious Diseases, undated (Box 11)
      - Persons, undated (Box 11)
      - Place, undated (Box 11)
      - Time, undated (Box 11)
      - Causality, undated (Box 11)
      - Insects, undated (Box 11)
      - Chronic Disease, undated (Box 11)
      - Cross-section, undated (Box 12)
    - Nature of Addictive Behaviors, 1990-1999 (Box 12)
      - Handouts and General Materials, undated; (3 folders) (Box 12)
      - Visual Materials, (2 folders) (Box 12)
      - Exams, 1995-1999 (Box 12)
      - Syllabus, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
      - Syllabus and Related Materials, 1992 (Box 12)
      - Syllabus (Box 12)
        - Spring 1992 (Box 12)
        - Fall 1995 (Box 12)
      - Syllabus and Related Materials, 1996-1999 (Box 12)
        - Fall 1996 (Box 12)
        - Fall 1997 (Box 12)
        - Fall 1999 (Box 12)
      - Student Papers, 1992 (Box 12)
      - Study Guide, 1993-1998 (Box 12)
        - 1993 (Box 12)
        - 1994 (Box 12)
        - 1995 (Box 12)
        - 1996 (Box 12)
        - 1997 (Box 12)
        - 1998 (Box 12)
    - Introduction to Health Counseling, 1988-2001 (Box 12)
      - Handouts and Course Materials (Box 12)
        - 1980s (Box 12)
        - 1990s (Box 12)
      - Exams, 1991-2001 (Box 12)
      - Syllabus, 1988-2001 (Box 12)
        - 1988 (Box 12)
        - 1990 (Box 12)
        - 1992 (Box 12)
        - 1993 (Box 12)
        - 1994 (Box 12)
        - 1995 (Box 12)
        - 1996 (Box 13)
        - 1997 (Box 13)
        - 1998 (Box 13)
        - 2001 (Box 13)
      - Study Guide, 1993-2001 (Box 13)
        - 1993 (Box 13)
        - 1994 (Box 13)
        - 1995 (Box 13)
        - 1996 (Box 13)
        - 1998 (Box 13)
        - 1999 (Box 13)
        - 2001 (Box 13)
  - U.S. Army Reserves Teaching Files, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Reserve Component – Alcohol and Drug Use Prevention, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Safety Science Workshop, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Union Institute Teaching Files, 1990-1991; undated (Box 13)
    - Union Institute Overview, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Psychology and Theories of Addiction, 1990-1991 (Box 13)
    - Issues and Controversies – Teaching Materials, 1990-1991 (Box 13)
    - Issues and Controversies – Syllabus and Handouts, 1990-1991 (Box 13)
    - Pharmacology, undated (Box 13)
    - Applied Statistics and Research Models, undated (Box 13)
  - Walden University Teaching Files, 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - Introduction to Public Health, 2000 (Box 13)
- Tenure and administrative files, 1964-2014 (Box 13)
  All files related to Promotion and Tenure are closed at this time. Consult Archives staff for further information.
  - Tenure, 1979 (Box 13)
    - Service (Box 13)
    - Teaching (Box 13)
    - Research and Creative Activities (Box 13)
  - Promotion, 1989 (Box 13)
    - General Summary (Box 13)
    - Research and Supporting Documents (Box 13)
      - Publications, (2 files) (Box 13)
      - Presentations and Grants (Box 13)
      - National Recognition, (2 files) (Box 13)
    - Documentation of Service (Box 13)
    - Teaching Materials (Box 13)
      - Basic and National Level (Box 13)
      - National Level (Box 13)
      - Classroom, (2 files) (Box 13)
      - Evaluation (Box 13)
    - Journal Samples, (2 files) (Box 13)
    - Manuscripts & Book Chapters (Box 13)
    - Research & Reports (Box 13)
  - CVs, 1964-2014 (Box 13)
    - 1964 (Box 13)
    - 1973 (Box 13)
    - 1977 (Box 13)
    - 1981 (Box 13)
    - 1985 (Box 13)
    - 1987 (Box 13)
    - 1989 (Box 13)
    - 1990 (Box 13)
    - 1991 (Box 13)
    - 1993 (Box 13)
    - 1995 (Box 13)
    - 1996 (Box 13)
    - 1997 (Box 13)
    - 1998 (Box 13)
    - 1999 (Box 13)
    - 2003 (Box 13)
    - 2012 (Box 13)
    - 2014, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Highlights, 1982-2003 (Box 13)
  - Annual Reports, 1973-2012 (Box 14)
  - Sabbaticals, 1979-2001 (Box 14)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 14)
    - 1985 (Box 14)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 14)
    - Scotland Travel Materials, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Scotland Travel Receipts, 1994 (Box 14)
    - 2001 (Box 14)
- Personal materials, 1947-2003; undated (Box 14)
  - Photographs, 1965-2003 (Box 14)
  - Poetry, 1956-2003 (Box 14)
  - Childhood Awards and College Materials, 1947-1958 (Box 14)
  - High School Writings, 1954-1957 (Box 14)
  - Communicating with Out There, 1965 (Box 14)
  - The effect of population explosion on the world's food supply, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Counseling philosophy and theories in an abortion information and referral service, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Utopian design for a complex society, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Theater – Clippings, undated (Box 14)
  - Tarot Card Reading – Clipping, 1973 (Box 14)
  - T.A. Clifford (Father), 1965; 1990 (Box 14)
  - US Army Reserves, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Short Biography (Professional & Personal), 2002 (Box 14)
  - North American Association of Benedictine Oblate Directors, 2003 (Box 14)
- Audiovisual and Removable Media, 1976-1999; undated (Box 15)
  - U-Matic Videocassette, 1976 (Box 15)
    - Teleconference, April 17, 1976; genreform: U-Matic Sony KCA 30 (Box 15)
  - Film Reels, undated (Box 15)
    - Booze and Yous, undated; genreform: 16mm film (Box 15)
    - Booze and Yous, undated; (2 copies); genreform: 16mm film (Box 15)
  - Data Tape, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Booze, November 13, 1990; genreform: 9-track tape reel (Box 15)
  - VHS Tape, 1985; 1999; undated (Box 15)
    - Pro & Con #1305 – Binge drinking and college students, March 3, 1999; genreform: VHS Quantegy T30 E45 (Box 15)
      Online Streaming in Media Collections Online
      https://media.dlib.indiana.edu/media_objects/rb68xv752
    - Personal Health (H363) Video of Course Session – Class Drugs, undated; genreform: VHS Scotch T120 (Box 15)
      https://media.dlib.indiana.edu/media_objects/rn301j61k
    - Personal Health (H363) Intro, July 25, 1985; genreform: VHS BASF T120 Chrome (Box 15)
      https://media.dlib.indiana.edu/media_objects/t148g056p
- Oversized Material (Box 16)
- Restricted Material (Box 17-18)
- The Saint Meinrad Archabbey Projects, 1954-2012 (Box 19)
  - Booklets, Essays, and Drafts, 1995-2012
    - Historical and Religious essays concerning St. Scholastica, 2001-2003 (Box 19)
    - Finding aids for this series created by Ruth Engs, 2012 (Box 19)
    - St. Scholastica drafts, correspondence, printed material, 2006-2011 (Box 19)
    - St. Benedict drafts, correspondence, printed material, 2007-2011 (Box 19)
    - North American Association of Benedict Oblate (NAABOD) drafts, correspondence, 2003-2012 (Box 19)
    - Professor Edward Shaughnessy drafts and correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 19)
    - St. Benedict: Hidden Meanings in His Story St. Meinrad Abbey Press, 2007-2009 (Box 19)
    - Oblate office drafts and correspondence, 2010 (Box 19)
    - Blog posts, 2011-2012 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2005-2011 (Box 19)
    - Items eliminated, notes, miscellaneous, 2010-2012 (Box 19)
    - First draft with edits, 2011-2012 (Box 19)
    - Page proofs, 2012 (Box 19)
    - An Updated History of the Benedictine Oblate Community of Saint Meinrad Archabbey: 1995-2012 St. (Box 19)
    - Finding Aid for An Updated History of the Benedictine Oblate Community of Saint Meinraid Archabbey" St., 2012 (Box 19)
  - Conversations in the Abbey, 1954-2012 (Box 19)
    - Selected Minutes of Finance Committee, 2004-2010 (Box 19)
    - Selected Minutes of Oblate Council, 2004-2011 (Box 19)
    - Conversations in the Abbey, 2007; (3 folders) (Box 19)
    - Drafts, table of contents, preface, acknowledgements, bibliography, miscellaneous, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Father Abbot Bonaventure's edits, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Chapter drafts, 2006-2007 (Box 19)
    - Post-production reviews, signings, publicity, correspondence, 2007-2011 (Box 19)
    - General correspondence, 2005-2009 (Box 19)
    - Finding Aid for Saint Meinrad, sample letter, questionnaires, monk list, 2005-2009 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence with Father Meinrad Brune, OSB, 2005-2008 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence with Father Joseph Cox, OSB, 2005-2008 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence with Father Harry Hogan, OSB, 2005-2007 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence with Mary Jeanne Schumacher, 2005-2008 (Box 19)
    - Brother Benedict Barthel, OSB, Correspondence and personal essays, 2005-2007 (Box 19)
    - Brother Benedict Barthel, OSB, Transcription and drafts, 2005-2006 (Box 19)